Ronak Bhatia

UI Developer

Summary

Over 6 years of IT experience as a Web Developer in Front-end design & development of applications using Java Web Technologies.

Extensively used HTML, CSS, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, AJAX, and JQuery, Angular JS, Node JS, Backbone JS, Dust.

Experience

Web Developer at Apple

October 2015 - Present

UI Developer at LinkedIn

May 2015 - September 2015 (4 months)

This project is designed to help the sales representatives to consolidate all information in one place with the use of this plug-in. There is less hassle of keeping track of notes and events based on an account separately. This plug-in is a combination of Gmail data, LinkedIn data and Salesforce data stored for employees.

UI Developer at AT&T

September 2014 - April 2015 (7 months)

This project is about using Adobe Experience Manager (AEM) and CQ5 to develop an environment that offer a share service for component key specification which serve up content for component application developers to write code that determines the information is going to display on the page. Developer make call to resource manager service to find out all the keys that they need to get the information required to fill out components.

UI Developer at HealthSouth

March 2013 - August 2014 (1 year 5 months)

This project is about full policy administration life cycle including quote, binding, rate, issue & service. This project includes multiple modules: Health policy administration system, customer management system, claim management system, business intelligence. Both clients and employees get reporting and charting solutions based on past data to ensure better solution-making.

UI Developer at UMB Bank

March 2012 - February 2013 (11 months)

This project develops Online Banking System that enables bank personal and business customers to access and manage their accounts through web. This application offers online services such as banking account management, credit card services, and online loan application. It offers Loan Officers the ability to collect

and review pre-application information to qualify potential borrowers, generate pre-approval letters, develop and delivers electronic monthly statements for customers on time. The system provides convenient and safe access for customer to manage their account at any time all over the world. The System also allows the underwriters to review, make changes, add, modify or clear conditions for any loan.

UI Developer at Purity Products

September 2011 - March 2012 (6 months)

Description:

Purity Products is a company which develops evidence-based nutritional supplementation and deliver them directly to customers. This project was about developing and redesigning Retails Sales System. This includes different modules such as Best Sellers, Health Concerns, Women's and Men's, Sport Certified, Specials and Customer Care.

UI Developer at Visa

January 2011 - August 2011 (7 months)

Visa has collection of tools used for monitoring the business performance and availability of endpoints as well scrutinizing the application and environment through monitors. My role is as a Web/UI Application Developer doing changes to the most existed Apps which are developed in non-web platform and transforming to the new web based platform by using oftechnologies like Jsp, html, CSS, JavaScript, iQuery, Ajax, Dojo, Java and Struts Framework

UI Developer at Dow Jones

May 2010 - January 2011 (8 months)

Self Service is a collaborated Subscription and Billing management application which manages DowJones (wsj and barons) users account online where the user can maintain their digital and print subscriptions.

Education

University of Central Missouri

Masters in Information Technology, Information Technology, 2009 - 2010

University of Central Missouri

Bachelor's in Business Administration, Business Administration and Management, General, 2006 - 2009 **Activities and Societies:** International Student Organization(ISO)

Ronak Bhatia

UI Developer



Contact Ronak on LinkedIn